kylie jue: Can you see the right screen.
kylie jue: Okay, cool. Welcome back to, and welcome to your final week of the quarter.
kylie jue: Today we're going to talk about another sort of like bonus topic that hopefully you'll find interesting and very relevant. If you go into any future computer science work and that is graphs and graph algorithms.
kylie jue: But before we jump into that. Go ahead and let us know, since they were do last night. What was your favorite part about working on your final project. We'd love to hear what you felt you learned or what you really enjoyed working on those
kylie jue: Alright, so here we are we're at the end of our roadmap and today we're going to be finishing up. Yeah. The last link data structure that we're going to learn as well as focusing on some real world algorithm because graphs are used everywhere in the real world.
kylie jue: And in general, we're going to answer the question, how can we represent an organized complex systems of interconnected components.
kylie jue: And for today's topics we're going to just first motivate graphs, why we use them. Then we're going to go into more specific definitions and terminology for the for the link data structures and then we'll talk about algorithms and how they're actually used in practice.
kylie jue: So just as a quick quick overview. I'm not going to actually do any sort of review from last week, hopefully you are well on your way with the Huffman encoding assignment.
kylie jue: But as a week eight overview, there isn't going to be any section this week.
kylie jue: And instead for today and tomorrow. We're going to do lectures on sort of fun topics that will prepare you for the real world posts. Yes, Windows XP. Today we're talking about graphs and algorithms and tomorrow but trip is going to give a lecture on multi threading and parallel computing
kylie jue: I mean, I'll give some instructions about how that's going to work with ship lecturing tomorrow. Later, during the announcements, so don't worry if you have questions about that.
kylie jue: And then on Wednesday we're going to have a wrap up and sort of a life after Windows XP lecture.
kylie jue: We are going to post this on Ed as well, but it will be linked in the slides, but we will have an ask us anything component towards the end. That will be a good portion of the
kylie jue: And the last lecture, and you can submit your questions in advance, using a Google form that we've linked there.
kylie jue: And then on Thursday. We don't have any class. So you should use that time to prepare for your final presentations.
kylie jue: And your final presentation should take place between Thursday and Sunday depending on when your section leaders scheduled them, you should be able to sign up for those via paperless
kylie jue: Alright, so with lecture tomorrow trip is going to be guest lecturing on a topic that is near and dear to his heart.
kylie jue: Which is multi threading and parallel computing and it's going to be a really awesome lecture.
kylie jue: Unfortunately, just like with yeah hours due to university restrictions we can't have miners who are under 18 join the actual zoom meeting.
kylie jue: But we are going to have an option for you to watch live. So the way we're going to do it is we are going to live stream the lecture on YouTube. So we will post a link to the YouTube Live stream so that you can watch in real time.
kylie jue: And then we're going to have a pin Ed post so that instead of using the chat, like you normally would during lecture that's in the zoom call you can just ask via ed and then Kylie and Nick or me and Nicole well
kylie jue: Will moderate and deliver those questions to Nick infield to trip in real time.
kylie jue: So you'll be able to attend like normal. Well, not exactly like normal, but a lot live as, as usual, it'll just be a little bit
kylie jue: A little bit different and how you're going to do that. So we'll post more links and instructions tomorrow morning for that. And as always, the lecture will be recorded for later viewing so no worries if you can't make it for some reason.
Alright.
kylie jue: So let's jump into today's content. So how can we represent an organized complex systems of interconnected components. We're going to use graphs.
kylie jue: So you may be familiar with a little company called Facebook or maybe something called LinkedIn. But all of these
kylie jue: companies use social create social networks using a social graph and Facebook in particular has actually the world's largest social graph that connects well over a billion people.
kylie jue: And Facebook keeps track of the connections in a graph data structure and we're going to talk about how that works later today.
kylie jue: Another way you could actually use graphs or something else you could represent using graphs are chemical bonds. So you actually have these atoms that was represented sort of nodes or items in your graph that are connected by bonds and that can actually be represented graphically.
kylie jue: Something else is an interstate highway system.
kylie jue: Flow charts, where you actually have you're moving through a flow chart that tells you the order in which something happens or the steps and once you do something
kylie jue: The internet could also be represented as a graph, where each location that needs internet or each specific point would be sort of like a note and then you have those points connected
kylie jue: To one another so that they can communicate
kylie jue: And that's another representation, a much more complicated looking but beautiful representation of how the internet is actually a graph.
kylie jue: Alright, so what exactly is a graph from sort of given you. There's a lot of really big motivations that we could use real world motivations that we can use.
kylie jue: For graphs, but a graph, more, more formally defined as a structured way to represent relationships between entities. So it's pretty big. So let's get a little more specific.
kylie jue: So let's talk about our very first graph. So this is going to be our very first graph, we have a graph that consists of a set of nodes connected by edges and, in particular, if we look at this graph. Our nodes are these big circles.
kylie jue: And the edges are the lines that connect them.
kylie jue: And so, in particular the edges represent the relationships between the specific entities in the graph.
kylie jue: So now if we go into some more terminology
kylie jue: There are a lot of different terms when we talk about graph. So don't worry if you find yourself getting a little lost in the terminology will summarize them again at the end. It's similar to trees where there's sort of just
kylie jue: A lot of words, you might hear when you, when people are talking about graphs. So the first is that two nodes are considered neighbors. If they're directly connected to one another by an edge. So these two nodes are neighbors because they're connected by this edge here.
kylie jue: A path between two nodes, similar to how a path was defined in a tree is going to be the sequence of edges. So, specifically the edges that are followed to go between the two different nodes. So between the green and the purple node you follow these two edges specifically
kylie jue: The length of the path is the number of edges. So in this case, the path is linked to in this case we count the number of edges, not the number of nodes.
kylie jue: A cycle is a path that begins and ends at the same node. So you start at the Blue Note. And then you also end at the Blue Note
kylie jue: And if we add an extra edge here. What actually happens to the graph. So this is actually adding an edge where the, where the node ends up going to itself.
kylie jue: And are we allowed to have them. Yes, we are. This is actually called a loop a loop is an edge that directly goes from a node back to itself and depending on the type of graph, you're dealing with
kylie jue: Or what the graph, you have is some graphs will not allow loops, depending on the information they're storing you may not want to actually be able to do that.
kylie jue: Alright.
kylie jue: And then these are some more properties about the graph themselves. Those are a little bit more on the features.
kylie jue: So some properties. I noticed reachable from another node. If you can have an actual path that exists between the nodes. So again, you can travel this way or this way to get from the blue to the purple nodes so
kylie jue: The purple. Notice reachable from the Blue Note and a graph is connected if all the nodes are reachable from all the other nodes. So you can pick any node in this graph and get to any of the other nodes. Therefore, this graph is considered connected
kylie jue: This graph which would still be you could still call this a graph on its own is not actually connected, right. You can't go from the purple node to any of the three nodes over here. And none of the three nodes over here.
kylie jue: Can reach either of the two nodes over here. So in this case, you have a graph that is not actually connected
kylie jue: And then the last piece of terminology here is complete a graph is complete. If every node has an edge connecting it to every other node so yellow connects to blue, red and purple purple connects to read
kylie jue: Blue and Yellow, etc. And there's a node between what if you take one given out and another given out there will be a note, there'll be an edge between it.
kylie jue: Alright, so this is sort of a summary, the initial terms were just sort of on the structure of the graph itself where you had neighbors, a path, the length of the path.
kylie jue: A cycle and a loop and then to talk about some of the properties graphs can have a node can be reachable from another node a graph can be connected. And it can also be complete. Have any questions on this terminology. Before I move on, I know that was a little bit of a whirlwind. So
kylie jue: Just I'll pause here for a moment. So you can take in a different terms.
haoming li: So the picture with two
haoming li: Graphs, or you say this one.
kylie jue: This one.
So,
haoming li: Do we consider them as one craft long grass, but not connected where we can ask, consider them as two separate points.
kylie jue: Yeah, you can. We would call this one graph. So it's sort of like if you're thinking about you're storing information and these three items just happened to be connected to one another. And these two didn't. It could be one graph.
kylie jue: But you could also take them individually and say, like, this is a graph. And this is a graph as well. But it's also totally fine to have these like disconnected pieces and or single graph. Yeah, okay.
kylie jue: Cool. Any other questions on the terminology. Before I move on.
kylie jue: Alright, so let's talk now, now that we have some sort of baseline terminology for describing graphs. Let's actually formalize different types of graphs.
kylie jue: So the first type. I want to talk about art directed graphs.
kylie jue: So these represents situations where relationships are Unidirectional and what does that mean, it means that when you're talking about the relationship. So you might be able to use a verb to describe what the relationship between two items are
kylie jue: That verb goes in one direction. So let's see an example. So let's suppose I follow Dwayne The Rock Johnson on Instagram, but he does not follow me back. And fortunately,
kylie jue: That is a unit directional relationship actual following itself is a relationship that both people need to agree to in order to
kylie jue: Go in both directions, but a single follow is uni directional so that fundamentally is a uni directional relationship inside the Instagram sort of social graph.
kylie jue: That just to note though that doesn't mean that you can't have a relationship go both ways. But again,
kylie jue: Dwayne The Rock Johnson would actually need to follow me back actively on Instagram for that to work. So the actual action itself. The following is fundamentally just going in one direction when you actually do it.
kylie jue: Alright, so that's what a directed graph means you can sort of represent the edges in this case with arrows, depending on the direction that that relationship goes
kylie jue: And then we have undirected graphs. Um, so, these represent situations where the actual relationship itself will be bi directional. So the verb will inherently apply to both entities and it won't matter what order you say the entities in so
kylie jue: For example, you could say something like, I'm related to my brother and he is related to me that relationship will apply to what to both of us. Right. It's not the case that like
kylie jue: You will not be a sibling of your sibling in any for any reason, right, but just wouldn't happen. So this is another example of an undirected graph.
kylie jue: You can see that all of these nodes are sort of connected by sort of one
kylie jue: Letter step or one difference in letter away from the other and man is one letter, different from ran and ran is one letter, different from men, so it doesn't matter which direction you go
kylie jue: The difference here is a bi directional relationship. And so the graph itself was fundamentally undirected.
kylie jue: So yeah, so when you're thinking about directed versus undirected. Think about what that actual verb or relationship is and whether it goes both ways.
kylie jue: Alright, so the next type of graphs or graphs that are weighted so these represents situations where not all the relationships between entities are equal. So what does that mean
kylie jue: So let's take, actually, let's go back to the chemistry example where you have bonds between atoms. If any of you have studied chemistry you know that the strength of bonds and the energy of bonds is not the same for a given molecule, right.
kylie jue: And so you could actually represent those those numbers between the actual
kylie jue: Atoms when the edge is a font. There's, there could be a number of representing the strength or the energy of that particular bond.
kylie jue: This is an example of airports and you could actually represent the edges as weighted edges as the distance between different airports. So again, this is a graph that is weighted were not all of these edges are equal in
kylie jue: In relationship, you can actually quantify the distance between them.
kylie jue: And then lastly, sort of, as the as the flip appointed you can have unweighted graphs and these are basically all the situations where the entities relationships will have equal importance. So all the edges have equal importance, just like here.
kylie jue: If we have a graph where we're only representing words that are one letter away from each other all of them all of the edges are only one letter.
kylie jue: And so they will have equal importance.
kylie jue: Right. So in summary, you can have a directed or undirected graph. And you can also have a weighted or unweighted graph.
kylie jue: And every graph will be either directed or undirected are either weighted or unweighted and you can think about them that way when thinking about what sort of information you might want to store in the graph.
kylie jue: So let's actually revisit our graph examples and tried to figure out
kylie jue: What each would be. So the first one I'm going to do is I'm actually going to do the social network. So I want you to think about, would it be directed or undirected and would it be weighted or unweighted. Give me a second. Before I show you can answer.
kylie jue: So a social network and also mentioned in each case of fees, which what would actually be the nodes and what would be the edges.
kylie jue: And so it depends on what social network, we're talking about right so if the nodes are people and the edges. Our friendships are follows
kylie jue: Facebook would be an example of an undirected graph right if someone's a friend of the other person. The other person can't not be their friend as well.
kylie jue: However, with the Instagram example you can have directed follows right because that action only goes one direction.
kylie jue: And in this case, you would they would be unweighted because you don't have friends who are greater than others on Facebook, they all sort of show up in your one friend list.
kylie jue: What about chemical bonds. You have the nodes, being the atoms and the edges, being the bonds themselves. And then this would be undirected.
kylie jue: Because, again, the bought one Adam that's connected to another Adam is it's going to go both ways. Well, and this could be waited, because you can talk about the strength of the bond.
kylie jue: And the energy of the bond.
kylie jue: Right initial interstate highways. So in this case, you have the nodes, being the cities and the edges is the highways are no roads and this is undirected assuming that you have
kylie jue: No one way highways and it's not roads. It's highway, so hopefully I don't think there any one way highways out there. So this would be undirected and it would definitely be waited, because you have the distance that the highway travels between the two nodes.
kylie jue: And then lastly we have flow charts. So with or not. Lastly, sorry. We have one more after this, but flow charts the nodes would be the events or actions the transitions.
kylie jue: Between the nodes would be the actual edges and then it would be directed right because you have to move in a particular direction through a flow chart.
kylie jue: And it would be unweighted although I suppose you could technically have a flow chart that's waited. But in this case, the one that you see on the right is most certainly in on weighted graph.
kylie jue: And then the last one is we have the actual internet
kylie jue: So the internet. In our case, you have different devices that are connected on the internet and those would be your nodes. And those are communicating with other devices on the network.
kylie jue: The edges themselves would be those connection pathways. How does your computer connect to the server of a social media website to get information and the server would be another node.
kylie jue: And this would be undirected right because you're able to communicate. Both ways between two entities and you need to be able to do that in order to get information between two points.
kylie jue: But it can be weighted or unweighted you can wait it based on sort of the literal distance a literal, physical distance between two nodes and how the information has to travel along the the physical network.
kylie jue: And you can also yeah it's mostly about location like actual physical location of the nodes of the devices.
kylie jue: Alright so that was just sort of to apply the terminology that we we talked about about different types of graphs, as well as the actual
kylie jue: Properties and structure of the graphs themselves. And so you can now start to imagine now that you sort of have an idea of how to formally defined graphs.
kylie jue: You can kind of start to see why graphs are everywhere. So let's talk a little bit more about how you would actually, how does this tie back to 106 feet right we're talking very abstractly, so far, but how would you actually represent them in c++ as linked data structures.
kylie jue: And so let's put it all together. We have, in many cases, see nodes connected by edges are links when discussing linked lists and trees and so graphs are just actually another type of linked data structure.
kylie jue: And so how can you differentiate between the three of these with linked list. You have this very linear structure right each node was connected to, and most one other node and you went in one direction through the linked list.
kylie jue: For trees, you can have nodes that connect to multiple other nodes, but in a very particular sort of structure right there are no cycles, there's a specific parent child relationship between any given nodes and you have a single special root node.
kylie jue: That is essential for you to have this sort of tree like structure.
kylie jue: And for graphs. It's sort of the wild west of the node world there are no restrictions and that's why they're using so many different places because they are really so flexible in terms of how you describe the links between the items inside of them.
kylie jue: So what does that mean actually more formally. So graphs can have cycles and there is no notion of a parent child relationship between the nodes. So that would be a cycle right we talked about what a cycle actually how that's defined in a graph.
kylie jue: And there's no root node. Right. So there's no parent or child relationship between any of these nodes, you can start at any of these nodes and say, like, this is where I'm going to start in my graph.
kylie jue: So in summary, graphs are really one of the most powerful and flexible really expressive abstractions that we can use to model relationships between like distributed
kylie jue: Entities and really remember when we're when we're using linked data structure that distributed identity identities entities, is what we're really focused on here until you'll start to see graphs everywhere you look.
kylie jue: And so how would we actually formally represent graphs and store them. So our first example is going to be something called an adjacent See List, and I'm going to walk through what that means.
kylie jue: Step by step here so we can represent a graph as a map. And so remember our map data structure from nodes to the collection of nodes that each node is adjacent to
kylie jue: So let's break that down. So this is, again, this is our example graph. And so we have a map. And let's suppose we have some node structures like we did with like less than just like we did with trees.
kylie jue: So we have a node as our key and we have a set of nodes as our value where the set of notes is what this node. The key is a JSON.
kylie jue: So if we look at our green node. What is the green note adjacent to the green node is adjacent to our yellow and blue nodes.
kylie jue: And so our key is going to be the green note and their value is going to be a set containing the yellow influence and we can repeat that for the yellow node which is adjacent to blue green and purple.
kylie jue: And then we can do that for all of them. So these are each, each of the individual nodes would be a key in our map and the value for each key is which know that specific key is adjacent to how many nodes.
kylie jue: And so how would you actually like programmatically represent it was this right, you could actually have a map of nodes to a set of notes, but there's different ways you could do it.
kylie jue: It doesn't, there's not just one way to form an adjacent See List. You could have a map of nodes to a vector of nodes, right. It doesn't have to be a set, it could be a vector.
kylie jue: Go about hash map. We talked about hashing at the end of last week. And so we can use this new hash map hash that data structure and we can
kylie jue: Substitute out the map and the set for hash map and hash set. I mean, you could also just have a vector of nodes, right, in this case.
kylie jue: Your node struct itself might hold the collection of its Jason neighbors. I didn't show you how this node struct is actually defined like it would have some sort of data.
kylie jue: But you could also define your node structure itself to contain the sort of like set of neighbors like a neighbor's data structure inside the structure itself. So there are a lot of different ways that programmatically, you could actually implement this adjacent See List.
kylie jue: And really the core idea. It's just that you have some sort of mapping that associates a given node with its outgoing edges and therefore, in other words its neighboring nodes.
kylie jue: Any questions on this on what in a Jason, see List is or how this works. Before I move on.
Alright.
kylie jue: So let's go ahead and go to an agency matrix. So, we can also use a two dimensional matrix to represent the relationships in a in a graph. So what does this mean so
kylie jue: Let's look at our, our graph or sample graph again. So let's suppose you had a two dimensional matrix. And really, you could think about this as a grid or an actual array because these will always be the same. It always have the same number of rows and columns.
kylie jue: And let's say on the on the column side here.
kylie jue: We have sorry in the column side here we actually have okay this is each of the nodes in our graph. So kind of like the keys and our map and in a row. What we're going to say is, okay, what, what
kylie jue: Other nodes is the yellow one. Can I get to and what other nodes, the green when connected to etc etc. So let's actually put this into practice. So let's look at this relationship.
kylie jue: We see that the yellow and green knowns are connected to each other. So what do we do, we go into our agency matrix and we put a one for the green node.
kylie jue: For so for the yellow node, we say, okay, put a one in the column for the green node, because I'm connected to that one. And for the green note.
kylie jue: Put a one in the column for the yellow know because I'm connected to that one. So anytime you have a connection here you're going to have to put a one, given that it's a undirected graph. Remember, if it's a directed graph. This might not be a symmetric relationship here.
kylie jue: All right. Now what about the yellow and the purple. You do the same thing right in this column, you have to make sure in this row you show that the purple is connect to the yellow. And in this row you show that the yellow is connected to the purple. So you put ones in each of these cells.
kylie jue: And you can fill that in for all of the other for all of these other sort of edges that exist in the graph.
kylie jue: So you can think about
kylie jue: iterating over all of the pairs of all the neighbor pairs or you could think about it is also just iterating over the edges, right, because that's going to give you all the neighbors.
kylie jue: And then you fill in your ones into your matrix. And remember, this is for the reason this looks really nice and symmetric, is that this is an undirected graphs. So every relationship will go both ways.
kylie jue: And then
kylie jue: For ones that are not connected you will do the same thing, right, you would end up putting in zeros, where the nodes themselves are not connected or you cannot get from the yellow know directly to the red node.
kylie jue: And really, you can think about just filling in the rest of that matrix with zeros, because they are not edges between the remaining pairs of notes.
kylie jue: Alright, any questions on the adjacent seem matrix representation versus the adjacent See List.
Nick Bowman: Oh. One thing I'll add because
Nick Bowman: This might be a question.
Nick Bowman: For the slides you would generally the trade off between using an address and see. Listen, Jason see matrix.
Nick Bowman: And it isn't seen matrix always like has to use the same amount of space, right, it's always going to be this sort of two dimensional matrix and with with all the notes on both x
Nick Bowman: And so you have a graph that has a lot of nodes, but very few edges and Jason, see List and you're going to take a lot less space to represent it.
Nick Bowman: And the nice thing about our introduces the matrix. The matrix itself has a nice sort of mathematical properties, you can take advantage of. But if you have a very sort of sparse graph. So there's not very many edges. The matrix can be kind of a very cool.
kylie jue: Actually, another question. Nick that I have for you is, sort of, so this could, you could easily see how this is sort of am I connected to another node you could easily replace this with weights. Would you be able to represent that in energy Cincy list.
Nick Bowman: Um, that's a good question. Um, I think that if you had an adjacent See List. You need some sort of additional sort of storage capacity to to store the weights of these
Alright.
kylie jue: So going forward, unless you're really state. Otherwise, we're going to assume that we're using an adjacent the list representation for our graph.
kylie jue: So just, that's just sort of a note for the, for the rest of lecture.
kylie jue: Alright, so now I'm going to stop here. Go into announcements and then Nick's going to switch in for the last part of lecture where we talk about graph algorithms.
kylie jue: But our quick announcements for today assignment six is do on Wednesday, this in a couple days at 11:59pm PDT and again reminder that this is a hard deadline so there is no grace period and no submissions are going to be accepted. After this time.
kylie jue: And make sure you do sign up for a final project presentation time on paperless or you should be expecting to present for
kylie jue: All the whole slot will be 30 minutes you're presenting for excuse me for about 15 of those minutes and then 15 of those minutes will be left for Q AMP. A and those will take place sometime between Thursday and Sunday of this week.
kylie jue: But yeah, that notice. Just make sure you block off an actual 30 minutes lot in your calendar.
kylie jue: And then, just a reminder again about the lecture tomorrow the trip will be giving I will post more details about that in the morning.
kylie jue: All right, Nick, do you want to go ahead and share your screen I can stop sharing mine.
Nick Bowman: Alright, cool. So what will basically talk about
Nick Bowman: In the second half of class today is basically thinking about. So kind of just talked about, you know, there are lots of real world scenarios in which you can represent
Nick Bowman: The structure of of data in a graph and then so obviously kind of the natural question from there is like how do you actually sort of do things with that data. So we're talking about the terminology that we need to know
Nick Bowman: And it's now the question is going to be how can we actually sort of what algorithms exist that operate on the data in graphs. And so, and
Nick Bowman: And where we'll start off with is kind of where we started off with all of our other link data structures, right, the very first algorithms that we wrote for the cliffs.
Nick Bowman: And for trees was basically just reversals right how do we sort of visit all of the nodes in the graph. And what are the different ways in which we actually can do this this presentation in this person.
Nick Bowman: And so if you remember what we saw with singly linked lists right and what Katie mentioned right there was always this this sort of one flow direction, we always had to sort of start at the front and go forwards.
Nick Bowman: So there's pretty much only one way to iterate over thing for start at the beginning and go to the end.
Nick Bowman: And then when we saw the trees right we saw that expand a little bit with with trees because of the fact that we actually had to neighbors and and to some trees that we're branching off from us.
Nick Bowman: We define these sort of three different torso strategies where the order in which you process the current node, it's left sub tree that's right sub tree can get sort of mixed around
Nick Bowman: And and the result is that you can actually visit the nodes in the tree in very different folders and each of those orders.
Nick Bowman: Is useful for very different thing. So we saw that in order to reversals are nice on binary search trees because they give you all the results in order for storage reversals are really nice for freeing or the allocating trees things
Nick Bowman: With graphs rate. So, we define grasses, kind of like trees but like in the wild, right, like just no restrictions at all.
Nick Bowman: And it kind of makes sense that they're going to be even more ways to iterate over graphs and in every single way of iterating over these graphs is going to have different properties and different uses.
Nick Bowman: And so we're going to talk about a couple and we're going to, we're going to couple this idea of graph reversal with with the very related ideas if search
Nick Bowman: And we'll look at three different algorithms for actually doing that. And then we'll hopefully have a chance to actually look at some cool visualizations of these
Nick Bowman: And so the first thing that we're actually going to talk about is we're going to revisit bread for search. So actually, about six weeks ago now, which is pretty crazy. We had our very first electron, but for search in advance of when you all worked on seconds.
Nick Bowman: And Brett for search sort of worked on this key idea that when you're when you're sort of traversing. And when you're when you're
Nick Bowman: Sort of looking through a certain space and objects. You always start at a certain location.
Nick Bowman: And then you want to look at everything that the one hop away first and then two hops away and then three hops away. And so the original way that we saw this
Nick Bowman: Sort of illustrated was with the word ladders and we sort of had a starting word and then we looked at all words that were one letter away from the starting one and we looked at all words of two letters away from starting learning and so on and so
Nick Bowman: And we can actually apply this kind of mentioned earlier, we actually represent the word ladder relationship that we saw.
Nick Bowman: Earlier in this quarter as a graph where the relationship is like one means like one that are away and each of the nodes is a certain word
Nick Bowman: And so it makes sense that we can actually apply breath first search kind of directly to grasp as well.
Nick Bowman: And and so for example if we wanted to sort of traverse this graph, starting from there ain't going to note, F.
Nick Bowman: And what we could do is, again, just encapsulate the similar idea of first we visit everything that's one hop away. Then we visit everything that's two hops away and then finally we visit everything
Nick Bowman: And similar to how we saw when we were working for more letters. This algorithm guarantees that will always find the shortest path between the two places that we want to get to
Nick Bowman: And it always guarantees we're traversing things in an order that is defined by sort of proximity to the starting node. So we will always traverse the neighbors closest to the starting node first and then one further hop away and so on.
Nick Bowman: And and so you know the actual algorithm, you know, we're not going to quote anything today most of what we're going to talk about today is at a very high level.
Nick Bowman: But the algorithm for breath for search on a graph, if you sort of compare with the algorithm we saw six weeks ago is going to look almost exactly the same.
Nick Bowman: And what I mean by that is that it's going to sort of be based on this idea of using a cue to keep track of places that he visited and just sort of enforcement ordering among places that we visited
Nick Bowman: And so we always start off and then QQ we add our starting node and then basically what we do is we take one note out of the queue at a time.
Nick Bowman: And reprocess it, whatever that means, you know, we printed out or we know blog it or we just do something interesting with the note.
Nick Bowman: And then we just say all right for everything. That's my neighbor if I haven't yet visited it then add it to the end of the queue.
Nick Bowman: And then eventually, you know, after I process everything else in the queue. I'll revisit that moment, you know, all sorts of repeated concepts.
Nick Bowman: And and so the main difference here actually between what we're seeing on DFS defined on a graph versus what we saw with with letters is worth more letters were actually keeping track of the path themselves.
Nick Bowman: In grass that's a little bit more complex or we're just going to define it as
Nick Bowman: Only keeping track of them knows that we visited. And so this algorithm will give us this reversal the guarantees that will actually visit and things in order that is defined kind of
Nick Bowman: Based off of proximity to the started and there's two visualizations linked here.
Nick Bowman: So the first is actually an example of what this algorithm looks like when you run it on the example graph and our slides. And again, you should sort of see the same labeling and the same visitation process that happens that we saw sort of
Nick Bowman: Illustrated on the slides. And so that's just an interesting visualization. You can play around. But the more interesting when I want to show you is actually this one here and rich sort of shows off this nature of the fact that when you're traversing a graph with the breadth first search.
Nick Bowman: Algorithm, you're actually getting a reversal that sort of is dictated by by the proximity of nodes to the original movies.
Nick Bowman: And so you can sort of see this algorithm illustrated where the queue right uses we use this combination of a queue and and Jason seamless representation
Nick Bowman: To visit nodes and in sort of in order of their sort of proximity to the starting and what I like a lot about this visualization is it actually will show you the different
Nick Bowman: Levels right everything like 541 are all one step away. And so those are the first and then you have the nerds like six and nine and two, and three.
Nick Bowman: Which are all going to get visited second and so on and so on and and what I want you to notice. And we're not going to go into the details of how this works.
Nick Bowman: But if you actually keep track of the order in which you've been things in the graph.
Nick Bowman: You actually end up generating this tree structure right it's not it's not a coincidence is the structure looks like a tree.
Nick Bowman: And this is actually called a breath first search tree and what it defines is exactly sort of this reversal where you starting off at your start node and then you visit everything that's one step away two steps away.
Nick Bowman: And
Nick Bowman: And so
Nick Bowman: If you're sort of interested in learning more about some of the special properties of PFS you can sort of do a little bit of research on this idea of a breath first search tree. That's actually exactly what we see.
Nick Bowman: And so if we go back to the slides right and some of the interesting things about what PFS allows us to do.
Nick Bowman: Is we talked about that it has this great property that in unweighted graph, it allows us to find the shortest path, the community to notes right because it's always sort of visiting nodes in this sort of increasing kind of order away from the start.
Nick Bowman: But one of the downsides of PFS is it doesn't do anything with the edge rates if they existed. And so if we were trying to run an algorithm on a weighted graph.
Nick Bowman: Which, you know, we actually wouldn't need to do and sort of many real world applications. Right. A lot of the graphs that we saw as part of our examples where we did for one reason.
Nick Bowman: And so if we want to incorporate those weeds. We need an algorithm that actually does that. Right. Right now bread first search, kind of just ignores it and only goes by number of edges, rather than the actual weights or meetings.
Nick Bowman: And so what what's been most of our time talking to today is actually sort of an improved or better version of breath for search and that takes into account at once.
Nick Bowman: And this algorithm was called Dexter's algorithm. And it's actually one of the most famous sort of algorithms in computer science and it's super, super
Nick Bowman: Used and a lot of different applications. And so, but what will actually see is it's it's really just a slight modifications breath for search. And once we see what the key insight there is hopefully you'll be able to kind of appreciate how, you know, straightforward but powerful as
Nick Bowman: And sort of the problem that you know the real world context for a problem that we might want to solve. And this idea. For example, if you wanted to implement Google Maps.
Nick Bowman: So for those of you that have use Google Maps before right you implement you input your starting location and location.
Nick Bowman: And what it does is it calculates sort of multiple paths and it shows you, hey, this is the shortest path by time.
Nick Bowman: Compared to from where you want to start to where you want to get to and sometimes it'll show you multiple options, but it'll always sort of highlight tape saying like, hey, this is the quickest way.
Nick Bowman: And sort of as kind of talked about with the interstate highway example right a road network itself can really just be thought about as a way to
Nick Bowman: Right, so every start and destination location and can be thought of as knows that the graph and then the connections between these nodes are roads and streets and highways and
Nick Bowman: And all of that good stuff. But each of those roads are highways are ways to get from point A to point B are all going to have different weights. Right.
Nick Bowman: And. And if we think about the weights as representing the amount of time it takes to to actually take that route.
Nick Bowman: Those weights could depend on the physical distance the traffic at that point in time, it could depend on the stoplight patterns.
Nick Bowman: And for, you know, a system and a product like Google Maps. They actually have all that information and they're able to build this giant road road network with very, very precise suites.
Nick Bowman: That actually tell you this is exactly how long it's going to take you to drive on this road between point A.
Nick Bowman: And so if we want to actually sort of put that all together, we would want to be able to find the path through the graph. And that is the quickest basically dependent on edge rates basically as the lowest some of edge rates and starting between our starting point.
Nick Bowman: And so our question will be, sort of, how can we actually do this. And the idea is, is, like I said, going to be a very slight modification to breakfast.
Nick Bowman: And breath first search, we organize the nodes in the queue by basically saying everything that gets every time I visit UNKNOWN. It just gets out into the back of the queue and this sort of enforces this ordering where
Nick Bowman: Nodes are only visited in an order that is sort of consistent with their, their distance from the starting node in terms of the number of edges that you actually have to traverse
Nick Bowman: And the idea for Dexter is, is basically going to say, hey, take that and just make it a little bit more intelligent and rather than basing that off of the number of edges actually replaced that with a priority. That's dependent on the some of the weeds on that of the pack for that.
Nick Bowman: And so what data structure is really, really useful here. We're going to go from using the Q to using priority because now we have sort of a numerical number that's actually going to represent. Oh, the sort of total some of the analytics of meditating.
Nick Bowman: And so basically the modifications that we see to breath for search is we say that the very starting point is included priority zero
Nick Bowman: And then every subsequent node before it gets in cute. It's given a priority. That's equal to the current know that you're starting at plus the edge of the edge.
Nick Bowman: And the ordering of nodes in the priority queue actually guarantee is it will be visiting nodes in order of increasing sort of EDS weight or increasing distance from the sea. So rather than increasing number of edges, you have to traverse but actually like increasing
Nick Bowman: And and so if we take our pseudo code that we saw from BFS and sort of modify it into the extras, we see that really the major additions, is that we now have a priority queue.
Nick Bowman: Now every time we DQ a node, we also care about what priority. It has because that represents sort of its current distance away from the starting node.
Nick Bowman: And then every time a new new gets added to the queue we encounter with a new priority that's equal to the current priority, plus the address the reactor and controllers to get between the current node and under that
Nick Bowman: And then there's also this also sort of small caveat, which says that
Nick Bowman: If the node has actually been visited and shows up in the priority queue, we actually have to update its priority to be to be a smaller value of if the new sort of priority that we get for the small
Nick Bowman: And if you if you know the Stanford prior to that we're working with in Huffman and that priority to actually implement a helpful method called change priority.
Nick Bowman: That we can use up there. And again, we're not going to be implementing anything so that the specific details don't matter of time.
Nick Bowman: But really what I want you to take away here is Dexter's algorithm is this sort of extension of breath for search where the ordering in between visit nodes now is dependent on their priority and their priorities sort of encapsulates
Nick Bowman: The some of the Edwin that it took for the shortest some of the elevator.
Nick Bowman: And so if we, for example, wanted to see how Dexter's works. And we might ask ourselves, okay, how can we find the shortest path between San Jose and San Francisco.
Nick Bowman: So it kind of is relabelled some of the nodes in our original example graph. And also I've added edge weights. And so, for example, and if you know
Nick Bowman: The node between being D. You can think of this, for those of you that are very local. We can think of this as the one on one freeway.
Nick Bowman: And you can think about the edge between see me as the two at freeway and and so maybe these numbers tell us. Oh, there's actually a traffic jam on to me. So they're not a time it'll take us to go that distance
Nick Bowman: Is 17 minutes but the amount of time it'll take us to go in one on one is actually the templates and so each of these ways you can think of is representing the amount of time it might take to get between pointing up by following up road or by following
Nick Bowman: And so the way that extra work right is we'll start off with a priority queue will put in earnest well known and and then
Nick Bowman: And then we'll start the algorithm by saying, Okay, so first we we DQ the node in our queue. And then we start exploring its neighbors. And so we say, okay, well there's a neighbor.
Nick Bowman: My neighbor be I can get to be in nine minutes. And so I'm going to go ahead and put being priority queue 39 and I can also visit see in one minute. And so I'm gonna go ahead and put seeing the prayer do with with weight.
Nick Bowman: And now that I've explored all the edges coming out of San Jose, I can say, all right, I'm done with San Jose. I think discarded the same way that I would have expected it in breakfast.
Nick Bowman: But then, the key is in terms of the neighbors that we, that we have in the order in which we visit them. We're actually going to start exploring starting from seed.
Nick Bowman: And so, exploring from See we say okay I can get to my destination. He
Nick Bowman: And that'll take 75 additional minutes beyond what I've already traveled so far. So my total priority for this node. He is going to be 71 again, which is the sum of the current priority of the note that we're at plus the address that we just first
Nick Bowman: Then we can also say, Oh, I just found a quicker way to get to be right. So, initially I thought that I could only get to be in nine minutes.
Nick Bowman: But by traversing this edge here. I've actually found a quicker way to get to be so I can actually update the priority of the node in the queue and say, okay, we now actually have this clarity of to I can get to you in two minutes by taking this Alton.
Nick Bowman: Now, we're done. We'll see. So we discard it. Then we go ahead and explore starting from the are starting from be
Nick Bowman: There's only one edge that we can take. So that takes us to be. And again, the priority of D is the some of these current priority which has to and the edge way that actually have this road takes us
Nick Bowman: And then the very last step right is to explore from D. And again, we see a very similar process happen by following this know to eat, we actually find a quicker way of getting there. So it's almost like a detour that
Nick Bowman: Google Maps is able to find you. And so we want to update the priority that there's no thank you.
Nick Bowman: And but then we also find that there's a way for us to get to San Francisco as well. So we do that.
Nick Bowman: And then right so we're not done yet. Just because San Francisco is in the queue doesn't mean we're done yet. We actually have to keep going until we DQ the node, because when we dq, it is when we know for sure that that's the shortest possible
Nick Bowman: Yeah, so then we go ahead and DQ it and then now we're able to say, great, we've actually found that the quickest possible way that we can get from San Francisco to San Francisco.
Nick Bowman: That path has a way to 15 and and we know that that's for sure because of this property that Dykstra, again, Jesus, which is that every time with dq UNKNOWN. We know that it that the value that it has is the shortest possible paths to be found to be
Nick Bowman: And so the question that I have for you. And then we're not gonna have time to cover today. But how would you actually store information along the way to allow you to reconstruct the path.
Nick Bowman: Right. So in this case, we found what the value of the shortest path is. I mean, we'd be able to tell you, hey, it should take you about 15 minutes to make this journey.
Nick Bowman: But we haven't actually found the shortest path itself and that actually requires a little bit more sort of complex keeping track of information. So we'll just leave that as a challenge for you to think about how could you actually keep track of information to reconstruct that
Nick Bowman: And so what are the properties of textures algorithm well dexterous sort of allows us to find the shortest path between two nodes in a weighted breath.
Nick Bowman: And like I said earlier, this algorithm really is the basis of many, many different sort of powerful real world systems that operate on paper.
Nick Bowman: But as we always ask ourselves in this class, sort of, can we do better than Dykstra,
Nick Bowman: And one of the things that we, you might think is missing so far is a lot of times if we're going to use graph to represent sort of information in the real world.
Nick Bowman: There might be other information about the graph or about what the graph means
Nick Bowman: That might allow us to actually get to our destination using less steps, right. So we saw Dexter's was better than read for search because we didn't have to explore all of the nodes, right, we only have to explore
Nick Bowman: And the ones that were sort of the shortest every time. And so that I could actually get us to the destination before we explored all of our notes.
Nick Bowman: But can we actually do better. Can we can we use even less steps to sort of
Nick Bowman: Find our path and starting note to the ending note, while still maintaining that we're going to find the shortest possible
Nick Bowman: And so that actually will be sort of our last topic to cover for today.
Nick Bowman: Which is this idea of a star search
Nick Bowman: And a star search
Nick Bowman: Works like that. So again, we're going to talk about instead of very capable, but say that we're trying to find a path between the node a. And the node j in this graph to the right.
Nick Bowman: And if I didn't give you any other information about what this graph meant or what the context of the graph was
Nick Bowman: And you really couldn't do any better than just applying textures algorithm, you just have to sort of explore going outwards and you have to kind of, you know, do follow the process that we just saw to find what the shortest path.
Nick Bowman: But what if I told you that this graph actually represents a map. And so these maps or cities and sort of higher up in the graph and sort of North lower down in the graph itself and then sort of left
Nick Bowman: Or to the right as Eastern to the left is less. And what if I told you sort of this this real world context about what this graph means
Nick Bowman: Like could you actually use that information to to do better and. And the idea here is probably yes. Right, because you would say, Okay, if I need to get from A to j.
Nick Bowman: And I'm traveling like on a map, or I'm like driving in my car.
Nick Bowman: I should probably always be making progress towards the north, right, I might have multiple options about how to get there. Right. Again, I could take two at North or one on one North
Nick Bowman: But if I wanted to get from San Jose to San Francisco. It doesn't make sense to go Seth like to go south to LA and then come all the way back. Right. And that's very unlikely that that will be the shortest path between those two.
Nick Bowman: And so this idea of a star search him is on this idea of using sort of outside real world context or real world information to better inform our search process.
Nick Bowman: And what it, what is it, what is sort of how does it work for us to do that. And this algorithm sort of leverage is on this idea of what's called a heuristic and heuristic is basically
Nick Bowman: A way of incorporating external information or external knowledge and what this heuristic tries to do is it tries to estimate, especially sort of us some
Nick Bowman: Knowledge that it has to make a guess as to how far you know it might be between our current location, the destination.
Nick Bowman: And so heuristics are different for every problem, right. So a heuristic for a roadmap would be different than heuristic for an air travel now would be different for the heuristic for a chemical bond nap right if you're trying to find some some relationship there.
Nick Bowman: But what's important is the heuristic should always underestimate sort of the, the total as weights that you'll need to get to your goal.
Nick Bowman: The details. Why are a little bit beyond the scope of this class, but against it sort of come talk to me afterwards.
Nick Bowman: But if we overestimate the distance we actually lose the guarantee that will end up finding the shortest possible solution. So, or heuristic to always underestimate the distance
Nick Bowman: And the way that we use this heuristic. And the reason why a star search is really just an extension of breadth of Dexter's algorithm.
Nick Bowman: Is this heuristic just gets added on to the existing priority. And so now we have we have an extra component of a priority.
Nick Bowman: Which says, you know, wait, this know not only by the current sort of true amount of distance that we've had to cover to get to it, but also by it's it's sort of gas to distance from the destination.
Nick Bowman: So for example, you know, if I had the option to go, you know, take a road going north out of San Jose versus the road going south.
Nick Bowman: The, the end destination of the road going to the north is going to be a lot closer to San Francisco. So the value of the heuristic for that node is going to be a lot smaller than it would have been if I initially started
Nick Bowman: And and this actually results in this very intelligent behavior where the nodes that are with this algorithm explorers actually seem to know where the destinations and they sort of prioritize moving in the direction of the destination, which is accurately.
Nick Bowman: And so coming here six they might see include things like Manhattan distance and as the crow flies distance in temperature of distance. Again, we're not going to talk about what the details of those are, but if you're interested in those, feel free to sort of check them out.
Nick Bowman: And so what I want to show you really quick is actually this very cool demo.
Nick Bowman: That is this I would highly recommend checking out this website and but it basically just shows you it visualizes different algorithms.
Nick Bowman: Between a starting node marketing green and a finishing node marketer. And so if we have something like breath for search, right, we see the very canonical classic like sort of ringing outwards behavior that we might have known to expect.
Nick Bowman: And, but, for example, if there's a wall on the way. Right. We'll see that breadth first search actually sort of ends up exploring a lot of extra information to be able to sort of make it around this wall and and find that it does find the path. Eventually, but it's not optimal.
Nick Bowman: If we move to a star search, right, you can actually see something very cool. So if I get rid of the walls.
Nick Bowman: A star search was going to look really, really smart. So how does it work, it goes boom. It knows exactly which direction the destination is in because it's actually estimating the distance between every path of the search and the end the final destination.
Nick Bowman: So sort of almost has this intelligence about where it needs to go. And that sort of enabled, but it's heuristic, which in this case we're actually just using
Nick Bowman: And so if we, you know, put it on equal footing would say, oh, what if there's a little in the middle. What's actually interesting is, again, it always is trying to make progress towards the end goal as best as it can be as sort of defined by the constraints.
Nick Bowman: And so I I've spent a lot of time playing around with the visualizations on this, on this website. I highly recommend checking out. If you have a chance
Nick Bowman: But, but a star basically by incorporating the this value the heuristic in its priorities and gives us this sort of very intelligent looking search just kind of the pinnacle of of doing sort of track for success.
Nick Bowman: And so I want to talk about this in much detail, but I'll put it up on the screen right now so you guys can
Nick Bowman: Since we are out of time. There are way, way, way more graph algorithms out there that we didn't get a chance to talk about today.
Nick Bowman: And in particular, there's, there's lots of really cool algorithms and and there's actually a very cool time between crafts and actually machine learning algorithms.
Nick Bowman: And so there's a whole class at Stanford called CS 24 w that if you sort of were interested in the context of today's class and you want to sort of learn more about how graphs are using the real world.
Nick Bowman: I would highly recommend taking that class actually got to do a really cool research project for that class in terms of analyzing
Nick Bowman: The entire Wikipedia graph for the Knowledge Graph and generated from Wikipedia. So if you have questions about that come come chat with me afterwards and but there's lots of really cool and other algorithms out there.
Nick Bowman: And so sort of wrap up for today. Right. What are we see we saw the graphs are a very powerful abstraction for organizing data analytic data structure and, in particular, when we have complex patterns or relationships between things grass allows to encapsulate that and represent that.
Nick Bowman: The core idea of graphs, as they consists of node connected by edges and then graphs can be directed or undirected rated or unrated depending on the context of the data.
Nick Bowman: That you're choosing to represent. And then the last thing that we saw is sort of these graph algorithms allow us to find and explore very interesting properties of grasses to solve interesting problems, based on real world systems that are represented
Nick Bowman: So we hope that we know that this was probably a little bit of moral one, but we do hope that sort of sort of piques your interest about graphs.
Nick Bowman: And again, if you have questions about anything. We talked about from child because afterwards.
Nick Bowman: And then our summary for what's next, we're going to be continuing our discussion a real world algorithms and trip is going to be talking about multi threading and parallel computing tomorrow.
Nick Bowman: And so we hope to see you there for that. It's going to be really, really cool probably be the best lecture of the quarter so we we hope to see you all there.
Nick Bowman: So thanks everybody.
kevin yang: Thank you so much.
Jihe He: Thank you so much. Bye. Thank you.
gavin gee: Thank you.
louise marzolf: Thank you.
tomhal@stanford.edu: Thank you.
Jordan Lin: Just out of curiosity, um, one is like the
Jordan Lin: pathfinding algorithm that is I guess like mathematically proven to be the most effective in like all cases. So like if we were to average, but I guess runtime or whatever, for all cases like it's the most effective
Nick Bowman: So,
Nick Bowman: Interesting you
Nick Bowman: Know, so. And the reason why is right. So, I mean, you can use Dykstra, as a sort of a, an upper bound on you know dexterous can be applied to any graph, any, any way to graph and and it'll be sort of able to find kind of what it's looking for
Nick Bowman: And that will require sort of searching a certain amount of the search space, right.
Nick Bowman: And with things like a star, you can start to improve on that and but what's actually interesting is that heuristics are not perfect.
Nick Bowman: And they, they are estimates. They are guesses. And so they can take you in the right direction. Right. And when they work well. Right. We saw in this in this visualization that they work very, very well. I mean, they severely reduced the space of of what we
Nick Bowman: What we're being asked to search. But if your graph doesn't have a real world context that
Nick Bowman: That basically you know motivates a heuristic like an actual way to estimate or to know you may not be able to do better than extra
Nick Bowman: Right, so it's it's actually, it's not like a precise mathematical thing of like, oh, for all graphs, this is exactly the best way to do it because the heuristic itself will actually depend on the context, right.
Nick Bowman: And and heuristics. Like I said, aren't perfect. So I was actually talking with Michael yesterday. And he had this this this great way of sort of describing what the general contextual
Nick Bowman: Sort of thought behind it started is which is, you know, say you're driving somewhere you haven't been before you kind of reach a fork in the road and you know you can go left or you could go right
Nick Bowman: And you know, you have this idea, but that like, you know, you have the general intuition that going to the right is probably better. That's kind of your futuristic. So you start driving down that road.
Nick Bowman: And then you realize, oh, it's actually a dead end. So you have to kind of turn around and come back and you know go up the ultimate time and it's a heuristics.
Nick Bowman: Candy good and a lot of situations, they are good, but they're not perfect, right. And so it's actually designing good heuristics is actually more of an art more than this kind of concrete mathematical
Nick Bowman: Thing that we can say like this approach will be always optimal for all products that actually there's as far as I'm aware that they're not it doesn't exist.
kylie jue: And actually related to that question, could you go over again why you want the heuristic to always underestimate the path link as opposed to overestimating
Nick Bowman: Yeah, yeah, that's a good question. Um, so the reason why we need the heuristic to underestimate the, the distance
Nick Bowman: Is if the so. So again, if we look here. So the priority is always going to have sort of two components.
Nick Bowman: One other components is you can think of this week as the, the true distance that we've traveled so far to get to the current node.
Nick Bowman: And then the heuristic is is a guess right heuristic is a guess of how much further, we have left to travel and and the
Nick Bowman: Property that we saw with like stress is that every time we DQ to know and we knew that the associated priority that was there was sort of
Nick Bowman: Along with it when we do cute it represented that sort of true short as possible that like true short has value of the way I get there.
Nick Bowman: And and so when we start adding in heuristics. It's important that we don't ever
Nick Bowman: Over estimate that true quantity like it's very important that we don't set the priority of the node to be something that is larger than that, like actual exact distance between
Nick Bowman: You know the starting node in the destination note because if we do that, we will lose the property that when we, when we DQ it from the queue that
Nick Bowman: That like we're actually decreasing it with the shortest possible like true distance if the heuristic underestimate that's fine because we might we might sort of
Nick Bowman: In sort of DQ it and and sort of still have it in the correct relative location, everything else. But as soon as it starts overestimating the value we lose this guarantee that the every element that would be queuing we have actually found the exact shortest path to it.
Nick Bowman: And so overestimating with the heuristic would still give you an answer, you just wouldn't have a guarantee that it is the shortest possible between those two minutes.
kylie jue: So what that'd be like saying, San Francisco is west instead of North
Nick Bowman: I'm
Nick Bowman: Not quite. It would be like saying like, for example, like if the, the true amount of roads that I have to drive between my house in San Francisco is like 30 miles. If my heuristic. So, so you can imagine. Let me see if I can
I can
Nick Bowman: So, okay.
Nick Bowman: So like, if this is my house.
Nick Bowman: And this is San Francisco. Right. Or you can say this is San Jose and this is San Francisco.
Nick Bowman: Right so so ROADS RIGHT roads. Don't go in a straight line right like roads, you know, the kind of meander right maybe there's like a highway for a Ford stretch and then there's like some side streets. Right. So say that's like the the true
Nick Bowman: Shortest path between San Jose and San Francisco and like the total amount of miles that you have to drive here is like 40 Miles, for example.
Nick Bowman: And so a good heuristic or an allowable heuristic might be able to say, oh, what is the actual like total like straight line distance between San Jose and San Francisco, because we know that that you know say that this is like 25 miles. Right.
Nick Bowman: We know that that's like a rough estimate ray and a rough under estimate of the distance that I have to travel. Right. Like it's if the
Nick Bowman: straight line distance between San Jose and San Francisco is 25 miles. There's no possible way that I can drive less than 25 minutes to get there.
Nick Bowman: Right. And so this, this would be a good heuristic or this would say, Okay, I'm under estimating the total amount of time or distance off to travel.
Nick Bowman: But it's still giving me a better conception, because it's saying, oh, you know, I want to go in this direction. Right. I don't want to go like
Nick Bowman: Out here and then over there because like the straight line distance between, you know,
Nick Bowman: Like, I don't know. This is like LA, right, like the straight line distance there is like you know 600
Nick Bowman: Right, so it doesn't make sense for me to try to go this way and then back probably right. Probably doesn't make sense to go that way because you know
Nick Bowman: My estimate of the distance the straight line distance between those points is is much larger and what you wouldn't be able to do right, it would be wrong to say
Nick Bowman: And I don't even like I can't think of a heuristic that would overestimated. Listen, because like
Nick Bowman: It's kind of actually hard to do that. But, like, say you just got this wrong and you use some for some reason assigned like said, oh, the straight line distance between between San Jose and San Francisco is like 60 miles. Well, your heuristic. What would now sort of
Nick Bowman: Cloud, the fact that the true distance shortest distance is 40 miles, and that would just cause all sorts of weird behavior in terms of how notes get nice and so that's sort of that's kind of a general overview of how you might sort of apply heuristics and like, I'm not
Nick Bowman: Does that, is that clear thing though.
Okay.
Nick Bowman: Yeah, I'm on the note of the lectures, I have to manually flip the switch on each one saw this lecture.
Nick Bowman: I just
Nick Bowman: I never do it.
edouard des: Yep, just audio check. Can you hear me. Yeah.
edouard des: Okay, perfect. Yeah. So I had a question about whether or not these because the traveling salesman problem is still unsolved, though, with all these algorithms. And the idea that you can't
edouard des: You can't solve it faster than by actually, can you like videos. And I guess my question is, do that, do you solve the traveling salesman problem.
edouard des: So,
Nick Bowman: So, no, no. That's a good question, the traveling salesman problem is, is one of the problems which no
Nick Bowman: efficient solution exists to find the optimal route. But what you'll find if you're looking to algorithms that can be used to solve this problem. And they use lots of heuristics and guesses to find approximate solutions.
Nick Bowman: And so yeah, so they can they can sort of find approximate solutions to things and but no there is no
Nick Bowman: Actually, the only way you could find an exact solution to the traveling salesman problem action would be a precursor backtracking or or with a, with an approach that actually are numerous all possible paths between cities.
Nick Bowman: But you can get very close you can you can you can give it a very good estimate of the true solution.
Nick Bowman: By making me taking advantage of some of the graph algorithms that we've seen and making use of heuristics along
edouard des: And the reason we don't want to enumerate through every single possible on node is because that would take too long. I'd like for you. You can have your GPS or I guess Google looking for every single like possible route.
edouard des: To get to where you want to go if it's only like 15 minutes away that that wouldn't be efficient from the competition. Oh.
Nick Bowman: Yeah, exactly. If you think about how massive
Nick Bowman: And giant like Google's road network map is right and
Nick Bowman: We want to make sure to be using pathfinding algorithms, you know, to find your destination from point A to point B that are efficient as possible. Right.
Nick Bowman: Like, you don't want to go into the Google Maps app and type in, like, yeah, I want to go from here to my friends house that's 10 minutes away. And it takes 10 minutes for it to like actually just
edouard des: Traverse yeah
Nick Bowman: So, so, yeah. So, so things like
Nick Bowman: Dykstra, and a star like improvements upon
edouard des: Algorithms.
Nick Bowman: Sort of by
Nick Bowman: reducing the amount of local intermediate location gifted visit while still guaranteeing that will find either the shortest path or very close to the first
And effectively, give computer intuition.
edouard des: They do, yeah. Huge
Nick Bowman: heuristics are that's actually really how I want you to think about heuristics are really just a way of
Nick Bowman: Of kind of overlaying human intuition about a problem and giving it to the computer, right, like it's the same way. Like, just by by adding this heuristic. Here we've somehow just given
Nick Bowman: We've given the computer, the intuition that it should always be searching towards the right. Right. And
Nick Bowman: It's just like it's kind of crazy that it
Nick Bowman: That it can get away with that right but it's like it's got this like
Nick Bowman: It knows right like it's, I'm not going to go around the wall in this direction, right, because that's not taking me closer to my destination. Right. I am going to sort of
Nick Bowman: Directly go as much as possible. I'm going to come in and directly go towards this this route. Right. I can even like say like I can build like this sort of
Nick Bowman: Structure around it and it'll, it'll still find its way around it right at all. It's, yeah, it's just very, it looks very smart, and it is very much
edouard des: Like putting human intuition.
Thank you.
edouard des: Actually, if there are no other questions mass another one on if there are other questions we asked one on them. Sorry, man.
edouard des: I'm sure users, it's not the right time to do that.
Nick Bowman: I just wonder
edouard des: About Andy Hoffman encoding trees, if we have one more sending them the encoded tree and we send the characters, along with the characters have to be encoded somehow as well, right, like the basic characters that are going to be used to map out the the encoding have to be encoded themselves.
Nick Bowman: Yes. And, and the way that the computer stores those characters themselves is most often using masking
Nick Bowman: Right, but it's the difference between storing
Nick Bowman: Every character in the message using ASCII
Nick Bowman: Rate versus building this encoding table that allows us to generate this like efficient intermediate representation. And so we start off with ASCII
Nick Bowman: We moved to this very efficient representation defined by our coding tree and at the very end we go back to ask you, right, because asking is, what's readable and understandable by the human right. But you're right, like the actual
Nick Bowman: Characters stored inside
Nick Bowman: The nodes are gonna be stored as
edouard des: An alternative to ask you, sort of, like, in addition to it to make it easier to sort of send and share
edouard des: So you don't
Think
Nick Bowman: It's just an alternative coding scheme, right, that happens to be
Nick Bowman: More space efficient right
Nick Bowman: I mean it. It is an alternative to ask you, right, like we are no longer transmitting our message in asking me right we are using a new
Nick Bowman: Representation system like yes it does work hand in hand with it. But, but I would say it is it is an alternative right like we could translate the content of our message you know entirely encoded in essence characters or recruiting code it using sort of this different representations
edouard des: And may I ask, it's like, is this Unicode also use ask you then I'm just, I'm just like a whole other question.
Nick Bowman: Well, you know, code is a different encoding.
Nick Bowman: Like
edouard des: Completely like it's a variable bit length as well. Right.
edouard des: Yeah, it's just a completely different like
Nick Bowman: I don't know how much relationship there is between the two. But like, it's just like
Nick Bowman: You. I mean, it's just like English and Spanish or different languages, right, like it is.
Like
edouard des: It's not built the top of, like, it's not all. It sounds like it's kind of like husband, but not really. We shouldn't see it as like being happened thing.
Nick Bowman: I mean, I don't know a ton about a unicode work. So I'm not going to answer that.
Nick Bowman: Yeah, it's not Huffman
Nick Bowman: It is it is distinctly different from that as
edouard des: Well, okay, thank you.
Nick Bowman: Any last questions.
I don't think so.